(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T22:58:19.935677",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
目覚めの合図
A signal to wake up,
スマホが踊る
my smartphone dances.
そして半分眠った瞳で
And with eyes half-asleep,
心の設定は A=440Hz
my heart's tuning is set to A=440Hz.
今日のリズムは合言葉で合わせよう
Let's match today's rhythm with a secret password.
ドゥル ドゥル ドゥル ドゥル ドゥ
Duru duru duru duru du
一歩前にレガート 深呼吸
One step forward legato, take a deep breath.
会う前には二度の瞬き
Blink twice before we meet.
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Let's play our Monday promise.
ねぇ、君と僕の合図
Hey, the signal between you and me.
You & 合図
You & signal
もう一歩を
Take one more step,
踏み出して
step forward,
合わせてみよう
let's align our steps together.
(You & 合図)
(You & signal)
なんでマンデー
Why Monday?
どうしてサンデー
How come Sunday?
明日へ弾んでいたいの
I want to bounce into tomorrow.
タクトをシュッ・シュッ
Flick the baton, swish swish!
拍手をパン・パン
Clap your hands, clap clap!
ここからは
From here on,
すべてダ・カーポ
everything is Da Capo.
日曜日のアウトロを飛び越えて
Leaping over Sunday's outro,
待ってるよ
I'm waiting for you.
明日よ来ないでと願ってしまうほど
So much so that I wish tomorrow wouldn't come,
あなたを待ちわびる時間すらも愛おしい
even the time spent waiting for you is precious.
一歩前にレガート 深呼吸
One step forward legato, deep breath,
スタッカートで二度の瞬き
blink twice in staccato,
月曜の約束を奏でよう
let's play our Monday promise.
ねぇ、君と僕の合図
Hey, the signal between you and me.
奏でよう
Let's play it.
ね、叶うよ
Hey, it will come true.
私たちだけの合図
The signal meant only for us.
Everyday anyway ぼくらの合図
Everyday anyway, our signal.
どんな夢を見に行こうか
What kind of dream shall we go see?
正しさばかりに恐れおののかないで
Don't cower in fear over what's right
自由自在に飛び回って
Flying around freely
ステップ・バイ・ステップ ビートを刻んで 果ての無いパーティーを続けようか
Step by step, carving out the beat, shall we continue this endless party?
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump onto this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Take off from this town tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the open sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Ride on this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Become the eye of the typhoon tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the open sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
代わり映えがしない日常の
In a corner of unchanged everyday life
片隅で無邪気に笑っていられたらいいよな
Wouldn't it be nice to laugh innocently?
無意味な旅を続けようか
Shall we continue this meaningless journey?
ワン・バイ・ワン 一歩ずつでいいさ 歓声も罵声も飲み込んで
One by one, one step at a time is fine, swallowing both cheers and jeers
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump onto this era
今夜愚かな杭となって
Become a foolish stake tonight
過ちを恐れないで
Don't be afraid of mistakes
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Ride on this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Become a nameless wind tonight
清濁を併せ飲んで
Swallowing both the pure and the corrupt
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Shake the earth
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Shake the earth
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Shake the earth
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Shake the earth
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump onto this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Take off from this town tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the open sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Ride on this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Become the eye of the typhoon tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the open sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
貴女の期待に飛び乗って
Ride on your expectations
今夜この羽で飛びたくて
Wanting to fly with these wings tonight
この大空を飛びたくて
Wanting to fly across this great sky
命生まれ 命生まれ
Life is born, life is born
この風に飛び乗って
Ride on this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Become a nameless wind tonight
清濁を併せ飲んで
Swallowing both the pure and the corrupt
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
イェー！
Yeah!
ヴィーナス
Venus
泡に乗って 海を越え 季節をまた連れてくる
Riding the foam across the sea, bringing the seasons once again.
貝殻に耳澄ます 静寂にも声を探す
Listening closely to a seashell, searching for a voice even in the silence.
教えておくれ この風はどこから吹いているの
Tell me, where is this wind blowing from?
そこにいるの
Are you there?
時間よどうか待って 僕だけが祈っている
Time, please wait; I alone am praying.
産まれる前に出会っていたよう 寄せては返す足跡も消して
As if we met before birth, washing ashore and receding, erasing footprints.
近づくほどに遠ざかるあなた
The closer I get, the further away you feel.
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた歌
Venus, a song written on the wind.
摘まれる花になりたい 物言わぬ貝でありたい 待っている
I want to be a picked flower, I want to be a silent shell... waiting.
絶やさぬ人になりたい 底知れぬ愛を知りたい 縋っている
I want to be someone who never lets it fade, wanting to know bottomless love... clinging.
雨なく花は咲かない 泣かずに憂いは枯れない 去っていく
Flowers don't bloom without rain; sorrow won't dry up without tears... fading away.
あなたが誰か知らないのに 探さずにいられない 去っていく
Even without knowing who you are, I can't help but search for you... fading away.
拾っていく 欠片
Picking up... the fragments.
夢に明け暮れ 寝息も秤にかけたまま 置いていくの
Spending days and nights dreaming, leaving even breathing on the scales...
忘れるよう願って 幸せを祈っている
...wishing to forget, praying for your happiness.
眠れるように握っては目覚め 大人になればざわめきも消えて
Grasping so I can sleep, only to wake up; as I grow up, the noise disappears.
息つくほどに遠のいていくもの ヴィーナス いつか思い出す
Things drift away to the point of making me gasp... Venus, I will remember someday.
産まれる前に出会っていたよう 寄せては返す足跡も消して
As if we met before birth, washing ashore and receding, erasing footprints.
近づくほどに遠ざかるあなた ヴィーナス 風にしたためた歌
The closer I get, the further away you feel... Venus, a song written on the wind.
背が伸びた頃 ねぇきっと会いましょう 砂に埋めた涙も還して
When we've grown taller, let's definitely meet; returning even the tears buried in sand.
生まれ変われどもう一度あなたの ヴィーナス 微笑みと生きていたい
Even if reborn, once again... Venus, I want to live with your smile.
ヴィーナス 巡るあたたかな音
Venus, the warm circulating sound.
はい！
All right!
ということで 始まりました！
And with that, it has officially begun!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026！
Otonose Kanade's Birthday Celebration 2026!
見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
ちょっと駆け足でね 2曲お届けしましたが いかがでしたでしょうか？
We kicked things off fast with two songs, but how did you like them?
たくさんコメント 8888 ありがとう！
Thank you for all the applause in the comments!
見えてるよー！ ありがとう！
I can see you all! Thank you!
はい そしてね ハッシュタグ こちら 画面にも出ているんですが
Yes, and as for the hashtag shown right here on screen,
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026 でいっぱいポストしてください！
please post lots using #OtonoseKanadeBirthday2026!
ちょっとこの配信が終わったら エゴサーチをするなり
Once this stream ends, I'll be searching social media...
いっぱいね 見に行くので 感想とか ここが良かったよーとかつぶやいてくれたら とっても嬉しいです！
...and reading all your posts, so I'd be super happy if you tweeted your thoughts and favorite parts!
ハッピーバースデー ありがとう！
Thank you for the happy birthday wishes!
こちらの配信ですね ライブのタイトル「IN PROGRESS」というタイトルになっています
So for this stream, the title of this concert is "IN PROGRESS".
ちょっとね どういう意味かなーって お前らいっぱい推測してくれたと思うんですが 大体合ってました！ すごい！
I'm sure you guys made plenty of guesses as to what that means, and you were mostly right! Awesome!
こちらのタイトルですね こちらの英語には「未完成」という...
As for this title, in English it carries the meaning of "incomplete"...
意味が含まれていまして
holds a meaning, and...
まぁ、ReGLOSSの今の未完成ながら進むというスタンスをこのライブでお見せできればなと思います。
Well, I hope to show you ReGLOSS's stance of moving forward even while incomplete in this live show.
はい、ちょっとまだ自分に完全に満足しきってはいないけど、まだまだ止まらず今に安住せず進んでいくぞっていう、そういう意味を込めての"IN PROGRESS"っていうタイトルにさせていただきました！
I'm not fully satisfied with myself yet, but I titled it "IN PROGRESS" to convey the meaning of not stopping, not settling, and continuing forward!
まぁ、ちょっとね、駆け足で紹介していったということで
So, I rushed through introducing them,
ちょっとお水飲んでいきたいんですけど、ダンサーさんたち、場を繋いでもらえたりしますかね？
so I'd like to take a drink of water. Dancers, could you buy me some time?
無理？
Impossible?
無理じゃない！やるんだよ！
It's not impossible! You've got to do it!
はい、お願いします。なんか面白い動きとかいっぱいお願いします。
Alright, please do. Show us lots of funny moves!
な、なんの動きですか？
Wh-What kind of moves are those?
ナイショ！
It's a secret!
ね、ちょっとパワハラ感みたいになっちゃいましたがですね、普段ReGLOSSのダンスの指導をしてくださっているとっても親しい先生たちですよ。
Hey, it ended up looking a bit like power harassment, but these are our close teachers who usually teach dance to ReGLOSS.
そうですよね？ / はい！
Right? / Yes!
言わせたみたい...
Like I forced them to say it...
じゃ、ちょっと今日の意気込み、なんか「うおー！」とか言ってもらえたりしますか？
So, could you give us your enthusiasm for today, like a "Woo!" or something?
頑張ります！
We'll do our best!
イェーイ！ダンサーさんたちもたくさんありがとうございます。
Yay! Thank you so much to the dancers as well.
ではではでは、次はゲストパートになります。
Now then, next up is the guest part.
最初は誰かな？ちょっと楽しみということで、じゃあ早速、次の曲行きましょう！
Who will be first? Looking forward to it! So without further ado, let's move on to the next song!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance.
眠れないくらい
So much I couldn't sleep...
情熱の火はいつしか いつつの日にか
The fire of passion, someday, at some point...
体から気づいている 焔はいつか消える
My body already knows the flame will vanish someday.
ねぇ 何も要らないはずだった
Hey, I wasn't supposed to need anything.
なのにまだ I'm so serious
And yet I'm still so serious.
あぁ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time...
あぁ ただ burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up, baby.
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet.
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But I'm sure it's not that bad.
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, let's burn it down, yeah.
燃えろよ 燃えろよ この炎 燃えろ
Burn, burn, burn this flame!
Yeah 千代も八千代も
Yeah, through ages and eons,
変わりもせずに
unchanged...
全部燃やせ八百屋お七
Burn everything like Yaoya Oshichi!
出でよ舞えよ火の粉
Come forth, dance, sparks of fire!
焚き付けるのが仕事
Fanning the flames is my job.
燃えるさまはお見事
The way it burns is a grand sight.
火遊びはしない
I don't play with fire,
ぬるいまね出来ない
I don't do lukewarm half-measures.
しけたカルマ トラウマ
Stale karma, trauma,
燃やし尽くすマグマドラマ
magma drama burning it all up!
この飽くなき渇き 青い炎みたい
This insatiable thirst is like a blue flame.
死は過去のひとつ隣
Death is right next to the past,
やがて総てひとつとなり
soon everything becomes one.
Love is dying
でもまだ消えてないから
But it hasn't faded yet, so...
忘れてみたい
I want to try and forget...
情熱の火はいつしか いつつの日にか
The fire of passion, someday, at some point...
身体は気づいている 僕らはいつか消える
My body realizes that we will vanish someday.
ゆるやかに若さを溶かして
Gently melting youth away,
泣かないで Why so serious?
Don't cry, why so serious?
あぁ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time...
あぁ ただ burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up, baby.
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet.
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But I'm sure it's not that bad.
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, let's burn it down, yeah.
Turn it up, turn it up, turn it up!
Sorry darling, hurry up
ああ まだ足りない
Ah, still not enough
Sorry darling, hurry up
ああ ただ奪って
Ah, just take it away
Give me fire, light it up, baby
燃やしちゃうぜ Yeah
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
But I still wanted to dance
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
Thank you very much!
誕生日ガール！
Birthday girl!
まず最初のゲストはカリオペ先輩に来てもらいました！
First off, our very first guest is Calliope-senpai!
初めまして！ Hi everybody! Yo, yo, what's up?
Nice to meet you! Hi everybody! Yo, yo, what's up?
It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday! やった！
It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday! Yay!
奏の誕生日をお祝いに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to celebrate my birthday!
いやいや、めっちゃ緊張してた！
No way, I was super nervous!
ラップする前「ヤバいヤバい、できない」と思ってて…
Before rapping, I was thinking, "Oh no, I can't do this..."
全然感じなかったですよ、そんな！
No way! I couldn't tell at all!
難しい日本語のラップ…
Japanese rap is so difficult...
もうバッチリ格好良かったです！
You nailed it, it was so cool!
頑張りました！
I worked hard!
格好良かったです！
It was really cool!
奏ちゃんも格好良かったよ。
You were cool too, Kanade-chan.
えー！嬉しい！
Wow! I'm so happy!
一緒に歌いたかったんですよ！
I've really wanted to sing with you!
私にも！
Me too!
カリオペ先輩のラップが大好きで…
I love your rap so much, Calliope-senpai...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
『Beyond the way』でも実は歌ってみたで…
I actually covered "Beyond the way"...
ご一緒させていただいたりしましたけど…
and got to collaborate with you before...
それ以来… じゃないか！
so since then... wait, maybe not!
そうですね、あんまり機会がなくて…
That's right, we haven't had many chances...
でも今回、凄かった！
But this time was amazing!
うわ、嬉しい！
Wow, I'm so happy!
ぶちかました！
You crushed it!
格好良い！それ奏もやりたいけど、今スタミナないからできないよー。
That's so cool! I wanna do that too, but I don't have the stamina right now!
スタミナ、スタミナ持って。
Stamina, keep your stamina up.
あ、スタミナ… 気遣ってくれてありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you for caring about my stamina.
水たくさん飲んで！
Drink plenty of water!
はい！あ、お水飲みに行ってこようかな。
Yes! Ah, maybe I should go grab a water break.
オッケーオッケー、Yes, yes, yes.
Okay, okay, yes, yes, yes.
Hi everybody! Kanade-chan mizu time. What's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
Hi everybody! It's Kanade-chan's water time. What's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
できた！
I did it!
ちょっと忘れちゃうと思ってたけど、できた！
I thought I might forget it, but I did it!
できたー！
We did it!
生歌凄い好きだから、今回誘ってくれてありがとうございます！
I really love singing live, so thank you so much for inviting me!
こちらこそ、ありがとうございます！本当！
Thank you as well! Really!
一緒に歌えて凄く光栄でした！
It was such an honor to sing together!
またやろう！
Let me know if you wanna do it again!
ぜひ！ご一緒させてください！
Absolutely! Please let's do it again!
お願いします。
Looking forward to it!
ということで、カリオペ先輩、ありがとうございました！
And with that, Calliope-senpai, thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！これから頑張ってね！ Good luck!
Thank you very much! Do your best for the rest! Good luck!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
You can do it!
Peace! バイバーイ！
Peace! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ということでカリオペ先輩との『火炎』でした！
And that was "Kaen" with Calliope-senpai!
次の曲行く前に、ちょっと暑いから…
Before we go to the next song, it's pretty hot here...
着替えてきてもいいですか？ちょっと待っててくださいね。
Mind if I go change real quick? Please wait a moment!
ふぅー！ジャケット脱いできました！熱気がね、すごい！
Phew! I took off my jacket! The energy in here is amazing!
お前らもいっぱい掛け声ありがとうございます！コメント見えてるよー！
Thank you all so much for all the cheers! I can see your comments!
では、早速次の曲に行きましょうかね。
Now then, shall we move on to the next song right away?
ゲストは誰か… 楽しみですね！
Who could the guest be... how exciting!
では、聴いてください。
Please listen.
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
Untold, sleepless dreamland...
あなたの見てる正体
The true nature of what you see...
誰も読めないカルテ
A chart no one can read...
不可思議 知りたいだけ
Mysterious, I just want to know.
[曲名: 不可思議のカルテ]
[Song: Fukashigi no Karte]
嘘も 現実も
Lies and reality...
どっちも真実だったの
were both the truth.
本当よ
It's true.
今日も ひとりごと
Talking to myself again today...
なんにも無理をしないで
Don't push yourself too hard...
わたし 愛されたい
I just want to be loved.
有耶無耶 さよなら 軽い眩暈
Vague goodbyes, a light dizziness...
あなたのいない現象界
A physical world without you...
誰も読めないカルテ
A chart no one can read...
カルテ
Medical chart
自意識
Self-awareness
溢れ出して
overflowing...
鼓動
Throbbing pulse,
世界像
worldview,
いつも 噛み合わないの
they never quite fit together.
痛くて
It hurts so much.
毎夜
Every night,
願いごと
making a wish,
なんにも疑わないで
without doubting anything,
混ざり 融け合いたい
I want to blend and melt together.
たわいない 分からない 理由 存在
Trivial, incomprehensible reason, existence.
あなたと残す後悔
The regrets I leave behind with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart nobody can read,
不愉快 繰り返して
repeating unpleasantries.
正しい夢は
Are righteous dreams,
かなしい声は
are sad voices...
美しい?
beautiful?
疑わしい?
suspicious?
羨ましい?
enviable?
ねえ、どれ?
Hey, which one?
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
Unspeakable, sleepless Träumerei.
あなたの見ている正体
The true form you are looking at.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart nobody can read,
不可思議 知りたいだけ
inexplicable, I just want to know.
終わらないことはない トロイメライ
There's nothing that doesn't end, Träumerei.
あなたと跨ぐ境界
The boundary I cross with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart nobody can read.
思春期 傷口 胸のうち
Adolescence, a wound deep inside my chest,
不可思議 知りたいだけ
inexplicable, I just want to know.
はい！ということで、にじさんじから町田ちひろさんに来ていただきました！
Alright! Joining us today from Nijisanji, we have Machita Chima-san!
お前らの皆さん、こんばんは！上から読んでも下から読んでも町田ちひろでーす！
Good evening, everyone! Whether read forwards or backwards, I'm Machita Chima!
わーい！ちひろさんにも「お前ら」が浸透してる！
Yay! Even Chima-san has adopted "Omaera"!
もちろん知ってます！ — 知ってるんですか！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Of course I know it! — You do?! Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！ — めでたい！めでたい！
Thank you so much! — Congrats! Congrats!
いや、ついやってちゃうんです、これ。
I just end up doing this pose without thinking.
癖なんですか？ — 癖なんです。
Is it a habit? — Yes, it's a habit.
それ、ちょっとリハーサルの時もやってて… やめて、ばらすのやめてください！
You were doing that during rehearsal too... — Stop, please don't expose me!
変な動きが出ちゃうんですよね。
Strange movements just come out, don't they?
でも今日はちょっと大人しくね、お話しします。
But today I'll speak nicely and calmly.
なるほど！ちょっと出てましたけど、全然大丈夫そうですからね。
I see! It leaked out a bit, but you seem totally fine.
そういえばちひろさんとはですね、先日一緒に「空想列車」という楽曲の「歌ってみた」をコラボさせていただきまして…
By the way, Chima-san and I recently collaborated on a cover of "Kuusou Ressha"...
本当にありがとうございました！ — こちらこそー！
Thank you so much! — Likewise!
お誘いいただいて本当に嬉しかった！ — 本当ですか！やったやった！
I was so happy you invited me! — Really? Yay!
でももう、ちひろさんの透明な歌声に絶対似合うだろうなって思って…
I knew your crystal-clear singing voice would suit it so well...
「空想列車」もそうだし、今回の「不可思議のカルテ」も絶対似合うだろうなって思って選曲させていただきました！
I chose both "Kuusou Ressha" and today's "Fukashigi no Karte" knowing they'd fit you perfectly!
嬉しい！一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy! I'm thrilled we got to sing together!
私も幸せです！え、でもなんか1個気になってることがあって… — 何でしょう？
I'm happy too! But there's one thing I'm curious about... — What is it?
「空想列車」のコメント欄に、なんか「化物」って書いてあったんですけど、ちひろさんのこと…
In the comments of "Kuusou Ressha", someone called you a "monster"...
それはいったい何なんですか？
What on earth was that about?
多分、別人の… 違う人のこと言ってるのかなって思うので、忘れてください。
They're probably talking about another person, so please forget it.
わかりました！こんな綺麗なお姉さんなのに化物なわけないですよね！
Got it! There's no way such a pretty lady could be a monster!
今コメントでも「化物」って書いてあったけど、きっと見間違いですよね！
Even now comments say "monster", but it must be a misread!
見間違いだよね！我々、ふたりとも清楚だもんね！
Must be a misread! We're both pure and wholesome ladies, right?
もちろん清楚ですよ！そりゃあね！
Of course we are wholesome! Absolutely!
はい！ということで、ちひろさん、一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです！
Alright! So Chima-san, I was so happy to sing with you!
こちらこそ嬉しかった！またねー！
Same here, I was so glad! See you later!
ふう
Phew...
ということでちょっとお水を飲んできてもいいですか？
So, can I go grab a drink of water?
ちょっとだけお水飲んできます
I'm just going to go drink a little bit of water.
まだまだまだまだ続いていきますよ
We still have plenty more to go!
次は誰かしら？あと2人ですね
Who's next? There are two guests left.
2分の1の確率。それでは楽しみに生きててください。次の曲！
A 50/50 chance! Look forward to it! Here is the next song!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
あれが正解なんて
What was the right answer back then?
誰の成れの果て
Who did I end up becoming?
なんだっての悶々
Agonizing over everything,
答えも欲しいのも
all the answers I want.
1個ってこれだけ
It's just this single thing.
悩んだって
Even if I worry,
しょうがないじゃんね
it can't be helped, right?
あれは夢だったって思うことにしたって
Even if I pretend it was all just a dream,
つら...
it's tough.
でも全然思えないんだけど
But I can't think that way at all.
助けてよフォロワー
Help me, followers!
抗うだけ
Just resisting,
若さに負け
losing to youth.
next, next
lucky lucky lucky!
アーリーオー
Early-oh,
割り切れたらさ
if I could just break it down.
オーリーオー
Only-oh,
楽なのにとか
it'd be so much easier.
aahh mm
もうヤダ
I hate this already.
なんという新世界か
What kind of new world is this?
あなた以外は
Anyone besides you...
あなた以外はいらない
I don't need anyone besides you.
張らないでよバリア
Don't put up a barrier!
あるはずの何か
If something that should be there...
あったならば
was actually there,
happy! jumpin' yeah!
あなたのその手と
If I hold your hand,
あたしのこの手を
and you hold mine,
繋いだらもう二度と離さないわ
once we connect, I'll never let go again.
あなたのその手が
If your hand
あたしのこの手を
grabs onto my hand,
掴んだら
from then on...
以後お見知りおきを my love♡
Pleased to meet you, my love♡
これで終わりなんて
To end like this,
アガれないままなんて
without ever getting hyped up,
泣いちゃって
crying...
ポンポンポン
Pat, pat, pat...
どうにかなっちゃえって
Wishing and praying
願って願ってね
that things will somehow work out.
ねえ朝帰りしたりしちゃうんどう？
Hey, what if I don't go home until morning?
なあもう我慢できん
I can't hold back anymore.
pain pain 痛いってば everyday
Pain pain, it hurts every day!
まよーていけるけどな
I can keep going even if I'm lost.
ブルベ夏なんで関係ないな^^
I'm a Cool Summer type, so it doesn't matter^^
誰よりもネコ
More like a cat than anyone else.
節操ないも結構
Having no principles is fine too.
あーしはあーしだ
I am who I am.
見といてよ ready
Keep your eyes on me, ready?
もう今日で終わらせたいなって
I feel like ending it today,
リスタートできたならって
if only I could restart.
でも無理よ
But that's impossible.
もう～～～～～
Argh~~~~~
what's on your mind?
アーリーオー
Early-oh,
割り切れたらさ
if I could just break it down.
オーリーオー
Only-oh,
楽なのにとか
it'd be so much easier.
aahh mm
もうヤダ
I hate this already.
なんという新世界か
What kind of new world is this?
あなた以外は
Anyone besides you...
あなた以外はいらない
I don't need anyone besides you.
張らないでよバリア
Don't put up a barrier!
あるはずの何か
If something that should be there...
あったならば
was actually there,
happy! jumpin' yeah!
あなたのその手と
If I hold your hand,
あたしのこの手を
and you hold mine,
繋いだらもう二度と離さないわ
once we connect, I'll never let go again.
あなたのその手が
If your hand
あたしのこの手を
grabs onto my hand,
掴んだら
from then on...
以後お見知りおきを my love♡
Pleased to meet you, my love♡
Na na na... Woah...
以後お見知りおきを my love♡
Pleased to meet you, my love♡
はい！なんと3人目のゲストは同じくにじさんじから戌亥とこさんに来ていただきました！
Yes! Our 3rd guest is also from NIJISANJI, Inui Toko-san!
まいどー！にじさんじ所属公式つむじ風の公式美少女、戌亥とこでーす！
Hello! From NIJISANJI, the official beautiful girl with an official cowlick, I'm Inui Toko!
戌亥...
Inui...
違う違う、戌亥とこですｗｗ
No no, it's Inui Toko. haha
戌亥とこ
Inui Toko
戌...
In...
戌亥とこ
Inui Toko
戌...
In...
戌...ｗｗ
In... haha
え～むずかしい～！
Aww, it's so hard to pronounce!
いいよ好きに呼んでいいですよ
It's okay, you can call me whatever you like.
とこさん！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Toko-san! Happy birthday!
ありがとう～！
Thank you~!
Happy Birthday!
イエーイ！
Yay!
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too! 初め... 初めましてじゃない
Nice to meet you too! Nice to... Wait, it's not our first time!
初めましてですよ！
It IS our first time meeting!
今日初めて会いました
We met in person for the first time today.
今日ガチの初めまして
Today is our legit first meeting ever!
いる？今日ガチの初めましての人、私達？
Are there people here meeting legitimately for the first time today? Us?
いないいないいない！
No no no!
初めまして！
Nice to meet you!
ね、ちまさんとは『空想列車』の歌ってみたでご一緒させていただいたんですけど、本当の本当の今日初めて...
So, I collaborated with Chima-san on the 'Kuusou Ressha' song cover, but today was really our first...
本当の初めまして
Really our first time meeting.
はい
Yeah.
もう今日初めましての時、あのー
When we met for the first time today, um...
とこさんが楽屋に来ていただいて、挨拶に来ていただいてありがとうございます
Toko-san came to my dressing room to say hi. Thank you so much for that!
いやいやいや
No, not at all!
その時にお弁当が奏の部屋にあったから
At that time, there were bento boxes in my room, so...
あった
There were!
「あ、よかったらお弁当食べますか？」って言って
I said, "Oh, would you like to eat a bento box?"
「選んでください」カレーだったんですけど、カレーと何か付随するものがあるお弁当だったんですけど
and said, "Please pick one." It was curry bento, with curry and some sides...
...なんですけど
...but
なんか、とこさんが
Toko-san
一言放ったんですよ
said something offhand.
「芋だ！」
"Potatoes!"
お芋が大好きなんです、私
I really love sweet potatoes.
芋？
Potatoes?
そう、お芋めっちゃ好きなんですよ
Yeah, I love sweet potatoes so much.
華麗... なのに芋？
So stylish... yet potatoes?
いや、お芋が好きやから
Well, because I love sweet potatoes!
「芋好きなんだ」って思って
So I thought, "Oh, she likes potatoes!"
芋があるお弁当だったから
And the bento had sweet potatoes in it,
「あ、よかった」って思って
so I was like "Oh, awesome!"
「じゃあちょっと芋一番大きいの選びますね」って言って
"Then I'll pick the biggest potato for you," I said.
そう、奏チョイスで
Yeah, selected by Kanade.
はい
Yep!
選んで、別にそれをこうあげようとしたわけじゃないんですけれど
I picked it, not that I was planning to give it to her or anything,
とこさんがそう採用してくださって
but Toko-san actually accepted it!
いや、それはスルーするでしょ
Well of course I wouldn't pass that up!
えー！
Huh?!
そんな、だってせっかく「これ一番お芋大きいですよ」って選んでくれたら
I mean, if someone goes out of their way to select "This is the biggest potato,"
「じゃあこれ」って
I'd definitely say "I'll take this one then!"
「じゃあこれ！いただきます」って
"I'll take this one! Thanks for the food!"
mechakucha ureshikatta desu
I was super happy about it.
あれ nanka ironna aji attandesu kedo, mou imo no ookisa dake de erandemashita yone
There were various flavors, but you picked solely based on potato size!
違うよ、ちーちー！奏が選んでくれたから
No, no, no! It's because Kanade picked it for me,
持っていったんよ、私は
that's why I took it!
感動しました！
I'm so touched!
えー！そうなんですか？
Eh! Really?
そうよ
That's right!
大好き！
I love you!
よかったら、あの...
If you'd like, um...
今後とも何か機会があったら
if there's another opportunity in the future...
もちろん！
Of course!
何か一緒にやりましょう
Let me do something together!
いくらでもやろう、一緒に
Let's do as many things together as you want!
本当ですか？ユニットも組む...
Really? Even form a unit...?
もう何でもやろう！全部やろう！やりたいこと全部やろう！
Let's do anything! Everything you want to do!
本当ですか？っしゃ！
Really? Heck yeah!
ユニット名...
Unit name...
「カレニス」で
How about "Karenis"?
ちょっと被るか...
Does that overlap a bit...?
っていうのは冗談で
Just kidding!
一緒に出来たら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if we can do something together!
ありがとうございました！とこさん、ありがとう...
Thank you so much! Toko-san, thank you...
こちらこそ！楽しみにしてます！
Likewise! I'll be looking forward to it!
ございましたー！
...very much!
一緒に歌えて嬉しかった！
I was so happy to sing with you!
またね！
See you!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ということでですね、次がゲストは最後になります
And with that, the next guest will be the last one.
最後はあの人！って
The last guest is THAT person!
みんな分かるよねー？
Everyone knows who, right~?
楽しみにしててくださーい！
Please look forward to it!
それでは、次の曲行きます！
Now then, on to the next song!
浪漫と算盤
[Romance and the Abacus]
主義をもって利益をなした言わば
When profit is accomplished as a principle, so to speak,
恰好つけ居食住の意義を宿す
It gives stylish meaning to daily living.
義務と権利双方を重んじつつ
While honoring both duty and rights
重んじつつあくまで
to the very end,
両者の割合を有耶無耶にしていたい
I want to keep both ratios vague until the bitter end.
玄人衆と素人衆皆々様賛否両論頂戴
Experts, amateurs, and everybody else, please give me the pros and cons.
億劫がんなよ野郎
Don't be hesitant, guys.
新しい技毎度繰り出したいで
I want to refine new techniques every time.
苦しくとも僕には分かってる
No matter how painful, I understand;
あなたも同じように独りで生きてる
you too live alone, just like me.
宇宙を因数分解したところで
Once you've factorized the universe,
自由と孤独だけが待ってるんでしょう
only freedom and loneliness will be waiting.
玄人であって素人であって労働者であって生活者のまま
Experts and amateurs and laborers, I'm still an ordinary citizen.
面白おかしくいさせて
Let me stay humorous.
煩わしい役毎度請け負いたいであ
I want to undertake the troublesome roles every time.
虚しくともあなたを想った日
Even if it's fruitless, whenever I think of you,
僕はお許されていく 夢と現を
I am forgiven, binding together my dreams and reality.
きっと
Surely,
そう浪漫抱えたら
if we embrace romance,
算盤弾いて
and use the abacus,
両極の真ん中
aim for the very middle of the two extremes,
狙い撃て お願い 勇気をくれ...
please, give me courage...
疑わしい相手なら
If it's a suspicious opponent,
いつだって
anytime,
自分 ずっと進化したいよね
I want to evolve forever,
答え合わせ
let me check my answers.
あなたを知るほど
The more I know you,
僕は正されていく
the more I am corrected.
すべて
Everything,
無駄じゃない
it's not for nothing,
ただ 生きようと...
just trying to live...
うわー！
Whoa!
マイクが遠いぞー！
The microphone is far away!
身体ブレた！
My body wobbled!
なんてタフな持ち方...
What a tough way to hold it...
ロッカーでしょ？
That's a rocker for you!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
スタンドマイクかっこいいじゃないですか！
Stand mics are so cool, right?
かっこいいですよね！
They really are cool!
おめでとうございます、本当に！
Congratulations, really!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
これちょっと受けるの。
This is kind of funny.
もう一回行こう！せーの...
Let's do it again! Ready, set...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
最後のゲストはすいちゃん先輩でした！
Our final guest was Sui-chan senpai!
はい！ありがとうございます、呼んでくださって！
Yes! Thank you so much for inviting me!
彗星の如く現れた大スターの原石、バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
It's the rough diamond of a super star that appeared like a comet, virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
皆さんこんにちは！
Hello, everyone!
音ノ瀬の皆なんですよね？
Everyone here is Otonose's fans, right?
あ、はい！そうです！
Ah, yes! That's right!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
音ノ瀬の皆さんはいつも「お前ら」と言われていますけれども！
Even though Otonose's fans are always called "you guys"!
今回の「浪漫と算盤」という楽曲...
For this song, "Roman to Soroban"...
すいちゃん先輩と一緒に歌ったら絶対にカッコいいだろうなって思って！
I thought it would be so cool if I sang it together with Sui-chan senpai!
まあ、カッコいいけどさ...
Well, it is cool, but...
生でやるもんじゃないよね！
it's not something meant to be performed live!
私本当にさ、昨日とかさ...
Seriously, yesterday and all...
「歌えるかしら」って、すごい不安になったけど...
I was so anxious, thinking "Can I really sing this?"...
今日合わせてみてね！
But practicing together today,
良かったじゃん！
it turned out great!
良かったです！
It was great!
めちゃくちゃ美声でしたよ！
Your voice was insanely beautiful!
「めちゃくちゃ美声でしたよ」返し！
"Right back at you with insanely beautiful voice"!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
コメント欄もね、めっちゃ良かった！
The comments section too, everyone loved it!
めちゃくちゃ相性良かった！ほら、「相性良かった」って！
Our chemistry was amazing! Look, "Great chemistry"!
嬉しい！また歌ってくださいよ、一緒に！
I'm so happy! Please sing with me again!
二人だけで歌うのは初めてなんだよね！
It's our first time singing as a duo, right?
「パンダヒーロー」で4人で一緒に歌うってことはあったんですけど...
We sang "Panda Hero" in a group of four before, but...
今回二人きりは初めてということで！
this is our first time just the two of us!
すごい楽しかったですし！
It was so much fun!
またね、呼んでくださいよ、奏ちゃん！
Please invite me again, Kanata-chan!
奏ちゃんのためなら飛んでいきますよ！
I'll fly over anytime for you, Kanata-chan!
ハモリという凄い難しい難題を一緒に飛び越えられて...
Being able to overcome the huge challenge of harmonies together...
飛び越えたね！
We overcome it!
嬉しかったです！
I was so happy!
頑張りました、私達！
We did our best!
アーカイブ残るし何回も聴き返してほしいですね！
Since the archive will stay, I hope everyone rewatches it many times!
はい！是非！
Yes! Please do!
奏ちゃんこの後もまだまだ続くと思いますが、頑張ってください！
Kanata-chan, the show still goes on after this, so do your best!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
それでは、失礼します！
Well then, see you!
はい！ありがとうございましたー！
Yes! Thank you so much!
ゲストの皆さんにね、たくさん盛り上げていただきました！
Our guests hyped up the stage so much!
ここからはソロでですね、頑張っていきますよ！
From here on out, I'll be doing solo performances, so I'll do my best!
まだまだ盛り上げていきます！
We're gonna keep hyping things up!
その前にちょっと準備とお水を飲んでくるので待っていてくださーい！
Before that, I'll go prepare and drink water, so please wait a moment!
行ってきます！
I'll be right back!
ここからは一気に5曲いっちゃいます！
From here on, we're going through five songs all at once!
最後には...
In the end...
シークレットだもん！
It's a secret!
最後のお楽しみにということで
So save the best for last.
それでは 次の曲聴いてください
Now then, please listen to the next song.
All Alone With You
[Song: All Alone With You]
誰かを愛することなんて 出来るわけなくって
There's no way I could ever love someone,
だけど誰かに愛されたくて
and yet, I just wanted to be loved by someone.
変わらない昨日がずっと 続いたとしても
Even if an unchanging yesterday continued forever,
どこにも行けやしないんだ 私とキミ
we wouldn't be able to go anywhere—you and I.
神さま どこへ行ってしまったの ねぇ
God, where have you gone? Hey...
返事はなくて いつだってそうだよ
There's no answer, it's always like this.
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I will go with you.
どんな罪も 背負ってあげる
Whatever your sin, I'll bear it for you.
道なき道を
Along an unpaved road,
歩いてくの
we will keep walking,
あなたと二人で
just the two of us together.
こっちに来て 私に触れて キスをして
Come over here, touch me, and kiss me.
もっとめちゃくちゃにしたっていいんだよ
It's fine to mess me up even more, you know?
いつか誰もが死んじゃって 忘れられてくなら
If everyone dies one day and is forgotten,
今確かなものだけを信じるわ
I'll believe only in what is real right now.
神さま気取りの人が言うの
People who play God say,
ねぇ 人は強いって
"Hey, humans are strong."
そんなの嘘だよ
That's a total lie.
Do you agree?
I will stay with you
あなたの手で 抱きしめてよ
Hold me tight in your arms,
思いっきり 怖がらないで
with all your strength, don't be afraid.
もう大丈夫 私なら
It's alright now, if it's me.
その手が汚れてしまったとしても
Even if those hands have become stained,
愛してほしい
I want you to love me,
私のこと
the real me.
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I will go with you.
どんな罪も 背負ってあげる
Whatever your sin, I'll bear it for you.
道なき道を
Along an unpaved road,
歩いてくの
we will keep walking,
あなたと
with you.
I will stay with you
愛してほしい
I want you to love me,
私のこと
everything about me.
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
No matter the sin,
背負ってあげる
I'll shoulder it for you.
Yeah...
give it back
[Song: give it back]
暖かい涙で
With warm tears,
ふいに目覚めた
I suddenly woke up.
焦がれた夢の続きは何処にあるの
Where is the continuation of the dream I longed for?
寂しいよ
I feel so lonely.
Please, give it back
いつになれば
When will I...
楽になれる
...finally be at ease?
押しては返す
Resisting the waves...
波に抗って
...that push and pull.
白い枕に
Burying my sleep-befuddled face...
寝ぼけたままの顔をうずめて
...in the white pillow,
同じ夢を願うほどに
the more I wish for the same dream,
冴えていくよ
the clearer my mind becomes.
Please, give it back
代わりなんていないよ
There is no replacement for you.
あなたの匂い
I can't remember your scent,
思い出せない波に拐われて
swept away by the waves.
夢の続きを捕まえに行くから待ってて
I'm going to catch the rest of the dream, so wait for me.
いつの間にか孤独ぶるには優しさに触れすぎた
Before I knew it, I'd touched too much kindness to pretend to be alone.
沁みていく
It sinks deep into me.
顔上げてみようか
Shall I try raising my head?
ひとりじゃないって信じてみたい
I want to try believing I'm not alone.
信じてみたいの
I really want to believe it.
生まれたばかりの淡い光に
In the pale light that was just born,
希望を見たの
I saw hope.
胸が熱いよ
My heart feels warm.
手を握っていよう
Let's hold hands,
迷わないように
so we won't get lost.
明日からまた
Starting again tomorrow,
選んだ道を進めるように
so that we can move forward on the path we chose.
お前ら！まだまだ行くぞー！
Everyone! We're just getting started!
ぶつかって
Clashing,
逃げ込んで
running away,
僕は
before I knew it,
いつしかここに立ってた
I was standing right here.
誰もが憧れるヒーローに
Wanting to be a hero everyone admires,
なりたくて
I wanted to become one,
でもなれなくて
but I couldn't be.
これぐらいじゃ届かないこと
That I couldn't reach with just this,
わかっていたのに
I already knew, even though I understood...
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
現実を歌え
sing of reality!
あんな風に空は飛べやしないんだ
We can't fly through the sky like that.
こんな夜に
If on a night like this,
意味があるなら
there is any meaning...
僕らは血を這う
we crawl through the blood.
耳鳴りが
Tinnitus...
こだまして僕に
echoing around, to me...
奇跡が問いかけるんだ
a miracle asks a question.
君の夢
Your dream,
憧れたヒーローに
the hero you longed to be,
今すぐ
right now,
させてあげよう
I'll make it come true for you.
雨みたいに差し伸べられたって
Even if a hand is reached out to me like rain,
嬉しくないんだ
it brings me no joy.
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
存在を歌え
sing of your existence!
君みたいに眩しくはなれないけど
I can't be dazzling like you, but...
こんな夜に
If on a night like this,
意味があるなら
there is any meaning...
僕らは血を這う
we crawl through the blood,
まだ地を賠う
still crawling the earth.
鼓動を知って
Knowing the pulse,
息を吸い込んで
breathing deeply in,
僕は遠慮するよ
I will hold back.
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
平凡を歌え
sing of the ordinary!
あいにくと神は信じないタチで
Unfortunately, I'm the type who doesn't believe in God,
すれ違いの物語よ
a story of passing each other by.
さよなら
Goodbye.
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
現実を歌え
sing of reality!
僕らは泥をはいつくばる者
We are those who grovel in the mud.
こんな夜も
Because even a night like this...
愛しいから
...is beloved,
僕らは血を賠う
we crawl through the blood,
ただ地を賠う
simply crawling the earth.
あのね
Listen...
私大丈夫
I'm okay,
maybe うまくやれるはず
maybe I can pull it off.
ずっと走った 息継ぎもしないまま
I kept running without taking a breath.
あっそう 終わりが来るなら
Oh right, if the end is coming,
別に寂しくなんかない
it's not like I'm lonely.
真実は
The truth is,
心の奥の方
deep down in my heart...
せつないまま 君のこと守れるのかな
Can I protect you while remaining in sorrow, I wonder?
どうか正真正銘のこの想いを
Please, this genuine feeling of mine,
立ったステージの上で
on the stage I've stood upon,
歌うから
I will sing, so...
大丈夫 世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, I know that the world is this beautiful,
分かってる 分かってる 分かってる
I know, I know, I know,
分かってるよ ごめんね
I know, I'm sorry.
じれったい
It's frustrating,
足りない
not enough,
こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
like this I can't love anyone.
止めない 止まることはしないの
I won't stop, I won't ever stop.
言葉 散らす なくしてしまうものばかりだ
Words scatter, so many things lost,
あぁ Luna say maybe
ah, Luna say maybe,
夜に紛れ
lost in the night.
愛せ どんな自分でも
Love, no matter who I am,
Maybe 色に染まるまで
maybe, until I'm dyed in color.
時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take time, but...
愛の輝くしかないこと ハイライト塗り続けるしかない
With only love to shine, I can only keep highlighting.
信じ... ちゃんと言わなくちゃ ねぇ
Believe... I have to say it properly, hey.
見えるものが
Things that can be seen...
続くとずっと...
continue forever...
君に半信半疑なそぶりして
Acting half-doubtful toward you,
心から空回りと
getting flustered from the bottom of my heart
空回り 最低だ もう一回やり直せるのなら
and spiraling, it's the worst; if I can start over once more,
素直になりたい なりたい なりたい
I want to be honest, want to be, want to be,
って願ったジレンマ
the dilemma I wished for.
このまま一人じゃ何もできない
Like this, alone I can't do anything,
全部決めるのは自分次第
deciding everything is up to myself.
初めて背中を見たときに
When I first saw your back,
カッコ決めた どこまで行けるのか
I made up my mind; how far can I go?
届くのか
Will I reach?
分からないよ
I don't know,
臆病がそこに立っている
cowardice stands right there.
3秒前 バックステージ 震える背中を君にあずけて
Three seconds ago backstage, leaving my trembling back to you,
これ運命と言って 愛は
calling this fate, love is...
きっと
Surely,
そうきっと
yes, surely,
偶然みたいな たぶん神様のいたずらです
like a coincidence, probably God's playful prank.
どうか正真正銘のこの
Please, until this genuine
想いが君の心にちゃんと届くまで
feeling properly reaches your heart,
ここで立ったステージの上で
here on the stage I've stood upon,
歌うから 待ってる 待ってる
I will sing, so I'm waiting, waiting.
だからこの場所を大切にしたいの
That's why I want to treasure this place,
これが正真正銘の私だ
this is the genuine me.
大丈夫 もう怖くはないわ
It's okay, I'm not scared anymore.
たまにつまずくことならあるけど
Though sometimes I stumble,
一番特等席で君の笑顔を見たいんだ
I want to see your smile from the best front-row seat,
私だけの特権
my own special privilege.
あぁ 見えない未来 手探り今日も
Ah, an unseen future, groping through today as well,
ステージの上で証明してみせるから
I'll prove it to you on top of the stage, so...
あぁ...
Ah...
ここにしかない ストーリー
A story that exists only here.
君にまだ話せてないことばかりあるんだ
There are so many things I haven't told you yet,
聴いてほしいの あのね
I want you to listen, you know...
Yeah...
今日は見に来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much for coming to watch today!
最後は新曲をお届けします！聴いてください！
For the last song, I'll deliver my new song! Please listen!
目覚めの合図
The signal to wake up,
スマホが踊る
my smartphone dances.
そして半分眠った瞳で
And with half-asleep eyes,
心の震えは A=440Hz
my heart's vibration is A=440Hz.
今日のリズムは合言葉で合わせよう
Let's match today's rhythm with our secret code.
ドゥルドゥル ドゥルドゥルドゥ
Duruduru durudurudu,
一歩前に レガート深呼吸
one step forward, a legato deep breath.
会う前には 二度の瞬き
Before we meet, two blinks.
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Let me play our Monday promise.
ねぇ 君と僕の合図
Hey, the signal between you and me.
ねぇ、君と僕の合図
Hey, this is our sign.
もう一歩を 踏み出して
Take one more step forward,
踏み出して 合わせてみよう
step out and let's match our pace.
なんでマンデー どうしてサンデー
Why Monday? How come Sunday?
明日へ 弾んでいたいの
I want to bound toward tomorrow.
タクトを シュッ・シュッ 拍手を パン・パン
Baton goes swish-swish, applause goes clap-clap.
ここからは すべてダ・カーポ
From here on, it's all Da Capo.
日曜日の コーダを飛び越えて
Leaping over Sunday's coda...
待ってるよ
I'll be waiting.
明日よ来ないでと 願ってしまうほど
So much that I wish tomorrow wouldn't come.
(La La La)
あなたを 待ちわびる 時間すらも愛おしい
Even the time spent eagerly awaiting you is precious.
一歩前に レガート深呼吸
One step forward, legato deep breath.
スタッカートで 二度の瞬き
Blink twice in staccato.
月曜の約束を 奏でよう
Let's play the promise of Monday.
ねぇ、君と僕の合図
Hey, this is our sign.
奏でよう
Let's play it.
ねぇ、叶うよ
Hey, it will come true.
私達だけの合図
A sign just for us.
なんと！最後の曲は、奏自身の2作目のオリ曲『You & 合図』でしたー！
And that last song was Kanade's second original song, "You & Aizu"!
パフパフー！
Puff puff!
ジャジャーン！可愛いでしょ？新曲のジャケットです！
Ta-da! Cute, right? This is the new song's cover art!
この後24時...えっと、21日の0時...ちょっと噛んじゃいました。21日の0時から配信開始です！
It'll be available for streaming from 24:00... I mean, 0:00 on the 21st! Stumbled a bit there. Streaming starts at 0:00 on the 21st!
もうね、すごーく可愛い振付となっているので、よかったら踊ってみてね！
The choreography is super cute, so please try dancing to it if you like!
さらに、この配信の後、MVも...えっと、21時10分からプレミア公開されます！
Also, right after this stream, the MV will premiere... at 21:10!
もうこちらの楽曲ですね、あの、歌詞もチラッと見えていたから分かっ...ちょっと気づいてるお前らもね、たくさんコメント欄でさ、ムカムカしていたと思うんですが...
As for this song, the lyrics were briefly visible earlier, so I think those of you who noticed were getting all excited in the comments...
あの、月曜日だったり、奏の要素がいっぱい込められている、そういう楽曲となっているので、よかったらね、あの、いっぱい聴いてください！
It's a song packed with elements of Monday and Kanade, so I hope you'll listen to it a lot!
はい！
Yep!
えっと、ということで皆さんお待ちかねのグッズ情報も行っていきたいと思います！MVも見てね！
So, let's move on to the merch info you've all been waiting for! Be sure to watch the MV too!
えっと、奏の生誕記念グッズ2026！パフパフー！可愛いー！
Um, Kanade's Birthday Celebration Merch 2026! Puff puff! So cute!
配信開始はこの後21時20分からだから、安心して最後までちゃんと見ていってね。順番に...紹介していきます！
Sales start after this at 21:20, so sit back and watch until the end! I'll introduce them one by one!
まずは、こちら！ジャジャーン！『奏と待ち合わせ！ポストカードフレーム』！
First up is this! Ta-da! "Meeting up with Kanade! Postcard Frame"!
今回のキービジュアルを『奏と待ち合わせ』をテーマにgomziママに書いていただきましたので、日常のワンシーンを飾るイメージで作ってみました！可愛いでしょー？
This time, gomzi-mama drew the key visual with the theme of "Meeting up with Kanade", so we made it with the idea of decorating a scene from daily life! Isn't it cute?
そのままでも楽しめるほか、なんか他のポストカードだったり挟んで別の絵柄で楽しむこともできます！
You can enjoy it as is, or insert other postcards to enjoy different illustrations!
2つ目は、こちら！
Second is this!
また奏が落書きしちゃったw Tシャツ！奏の落書きTシャツ第2弾！本当に今日は月曜日...
The "Kanade scribbled on it again lol T-shirt"! Part 2 of Kanade's scribble T-shirt! Today really is Monday...
もう月曜日盛りだくさんです！ハッピー月曜日！ということで月曜日Tシャツです！毎週月曜日にはこのTシャツを着てね、よかったら生活してください！最高！ありがとう！
So much Monday stuff! Happy Monday! So, here's the Monday T-shirt! Wear this T-shirt every Monday and go about your day! Awesome! Thank you!
えっと、3つ目は、こちら！『奏とおそろ！ネックレス』！可愛いでしょ？
Um, the third item is this! "Matching with Kanade! Necklace"! Cute, right?
今回キービジュアルの奏との、お揃いの奏モチーフのネックレスです！確かデビュー日が書かれているはずです、奏の！
It's a necklace matching the Kanade motif from this key visual! I believe Kanade's debut date is engraved on it!
よかったら...えっと、すごいシンプルでスタイリッシュなデザインに落とし込んでみたので、普段アクセサリーつけないよっていう人もぜひお手にとってつけてみてください！
We designed it to be very simple and stylish, so even if you don't usually wear accessories, please try wearing it!
そして4つ目、こちら！『明日月曜日!w』ひょっこりぬいぐるみー！
And fourth, this! "'Tomorrow is Monday! lol' Peeking Plushie"!
いやもうね、こちらの素敵な...素敵なフリップを持った奏のぬいぐるみです！画面モニターとかに引っかけて飾ることができますので、いつでも上から奏が『月曜日だよー！』ってお知らせ...いたします！イエーイ！
It's a Kanade plushie holding this lovely sign! You can hang it on your monitor to display it, so Kanade can notify you from above anytime that "It's Monday!" Yay!
最後にフルセット購入特典！パンパカパーン！として、数量限定で直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード、通常版は箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードとボイスがついてきます！
Finally, the Full Set Purchase Bonus! Ta-da! The limited quantity version includes a postcard with handwritten signature & foil-stamped message, and the regular version includes a postcard with foil-stamped signature & message, plus special voice tracks!
音乃瀬奏の決意表明！
Otonase Kanade's declaration of intent!
お前らへの感謝とこれからの意気込みをありのまま伝えるフリートークボイスになっています
It's a free-talk voice message where I share my gratitude to you all and my future determination as I am.
ボイスはフルセットを購入したら必ずついてくるから安心してね！
The voice message is included automatically if you buy the full set, so don't worry!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
That's all for the merchandise showcase!
みんな、今日は月曜日だね
Everyone, today is... Monday, isn't it?
そんな月曜日のお前らには、じゃーん！
For all of you on this Monday, ta-da!
犬！
A dog!
今回は犬です。今日は月曜日ということで
This time it's a dog. Since today is Monday,
犬のフリップ！今年ね、エイプリルフールネタを擦っていきますよ。ワン！
a dog flip sign! I'll keep reusing this April Fools' joke this year. Woof!
えーっと、この後メン限にてアンコールライブもやっちゃうよー！
Um, after this, we're having an encore live stream for members only!
このQRコードは何なんだ？
What's this QR code for?
アンコールではちょっとお前らのリクエストに応えたりするかも？
In the encore, maybe I'll respond to some of your requests?
ん、このQR...あ、いけないいけない！お前らが読み込んでしまう！
Hmm, this QR... Ah, wait, no no! You guys will scan it!
このQRを読み込んだら、えっと、メンバーシップに入れるみたいです
If you scan this QR code, um, it looks like you can join the membership.
ん、じゃあ見せないでおこう
Hmm, then I won't show it.
うぇー、見せないでおこう
Ugh, I won't show it.
え、見せちゃおうかな？どうしようかなー？
Eh, should I show it? What should I do?
はい！えーっと...
Alright! Um...
それじゃあ、あの、今日は本当に、奏のライブに見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Well then, thank you so much for coming to watch Kanade's live stream today!
前編生ライブというすごい奏にとっても挑戦的なライブでして
Since it was a fully live performance, it was a huge challenge for Kanade,
本当はめちゃくちゃ怖かったんですけど
and to be honest, I was super scared,
なんとか、すごくXだったりお前らがこう応援のメッセージを送ってくれたおかげで
but somehow, thanks to your supportive messages on X and everywhere else,
すごく、緊張もそんなにせず終えられたかなと思います
I think I was able to finish without feeling too nervous.
本当に見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブでまた会おうね！
See you again in the members-only encore stream!
ありがとう！またね！チャンネル登録してね！
Thank you! See you later! Don't forget to subscribe!